大语言模型非常善于将其输入转换为不同的格式
Large language models are very good at transforming its input to a different format
例如，输入一种语言的文本并将其转换或
such as inputting a piece of text in one language and transforming it or
把它翻译成不同的语言，或者帮助进行拼写和语法的修正
translating it to a different language or helping with spelling and grammar corrections
因此，将一段可能不符合标准的语法文本作为输入
So taking as input a piece of text that may not be
并让它帮助你纠正拼写和语法
fully grammatical and helping you to fix that up a bit
或甚至转换格式，如
or even transforming formats such as inputting
输入HTML和输出JSON
HTML and outputting JSON
所以，我以前写的一些应用程序有点痛苦，用的是
So there's a bunch of applications that I used to write somewhat painfully with
一堆正则表达式的应用
a bunch of regular expressions that would definitely be much more
现在用一个大语言模型和一些提示语就可以更简单地实现
simply implemented now with a large language model and a few prompts
是的，我现在用ChatGPT来校对我写的几乎所有东西
Yeah, I use ChatGPT to proofread pretty much everything I write these days
所以我很高兴现在向你展示Notebook中的一些更多的例子
So I'm excited to show you some more examples in the notebook now
所以，首先，我们将导入openai，同时
So first, we'll import openai and also
使用我们在整个视频中一直使用的get_completion辅助函数
use the same get_completion helper function that we've been using throughout the videos
我们要做的第一件事是一个翻译任务
The first thing we'll do is a translation task
因此，大语言模型是在许多来源的大量文本上训练出来的
So large language models are trained on a lot of text from many sources
其中有很多是互联网
a lot of which is the Internet
这当然是用许多不同的语言
and this is of course in many different languages
因此，这使模型具有翻译能力
So this imbues the model with the ability to do translation
这些模型知道数百种语言的不同程度的熟练程度
These models know hundreds of languages to varying degrees of proficiency
所以我们将通过一些例子来说明如何使用这种能力
So we'll go through some examples of how to use this capability
所以，让我们从简单的东西开始
So let's start off with something simple
所以在这第一个例子中
So in this first example
提示是将以下英文文本翻译成西班牙语
the prompt is translate the following English text to Spanish
你好，我想订购一台搅拌机
Hi, I would like to order a blender
响应是：Hola
The response is, Hola
me gustaría ordenar una licuadora.
me gustaría ordenar una licuadora
我对所有讲西班牙语的人感到非常抱歉
I'm very sorry to all of you Spanish speakers
我从来没有学过西班牙语，很不幸，你肯定能看出来
I never learned Spanish unfortunately, as you can definitely tell
让我们尝试另一个例子
Let's try another example
所以在这个例子中
So in this example
提示是，告诉我这是什么语言
the prompt is, tell me what language this is
那么这是用法语说的
Then this is in French
combien coûte le lampadaire?
所以我们来运行这个
So let's run this
该模型已经识别出这是法语
The model has identified that this is French
该模型还可以一次做多个翻译
The model can also do multiple translations at once
所以在这个例子中
So in this example
让我们说把下面的文字翻译成法语和西班牙语
let's say translate the following text to French and Spanish
你知道吗，让我们再加一个
You know what, let's add another
英国海盗
an English pirate
这段文字是，我想订购一个篮球
The text is, I want to order a basketball
所以这里我们有法语
So here we have French
西班牙文，和英国海盗
Spanish, and English pirate
所以在某些语言中
So in some languages
翻译可以改变，取决于
the translation can change depending on
说话人与听话人的关系
the speaker's relationship to the listener
你也可以向语言模型解释这一点
You can also explain this to the language model
这样它就能进行相应的翻译
and so it will be able to translate accordingly
所以在这个例子中
So in this example
我们说把下面的文字以正式和非正式的形式翻译成西班牙语
we say translate the following text to Spanish in both the formal and informal forms
你想订购一个枕头吗？
Would you like to order a pillow?
还注意到，我们在这里使用了
Also notice here, we're using
不同的分隔符，而不是这些双引号
a different delimiter than these backticks
其实这并不重要，只要它是一个清晰的分隔
It doesn't really matter as long as it's a clear separation
所以这里我们有正式和非正式
So here we have the formal and informal
因此，正式的是当你和某人说话时，他是
So formal is when you're speaking to someone who's
也许比你高级的人，或者你是在一个专业的情况下
maybe senior to you or you're in a professional situation
这时你要使用正式语气
That's when you use a formal tone
然后非正式的是当你和一群朋友说话时
and then informal is when you're speaking to maybe a group of friends
我实际上不会说西班牙语
I don't actually speak Spanish
但我父亲会，他说这是正确的
but my dad does and he says that this is correct
因此，对于
So for the next example
我们要假装自己是一家跨国电子商务公司的负责人
we're going to pretend that we're in charge of a multinational e-commerce company
用户的信息将使用所有不同的语言
and so the user messages are going to be in all different languages
因此，用户将用各种不同的语言告诉我们关于IT的问题
and so users are going to be telling us about the IT issues in wide variety of languages
所以我们需要一个通用的翻译器
So we need a universal translator
因此，首先，我们将粘贴一个各种不同语言的用户信息的列表
So first, we'll just paste in a list of user messages in a variety of different languages
现在，我们将循环浏览这些用户信息中的每一条
Now, we will loop through each of these user messages
因此，对于用户信息中的问题
So for issue in user messages
然后我将复制稍长的代码块
and then I'm going to copy over the slightly longer code block
所以我们要做的第一件事是要求模型
So the first thing we'll do is ask the model
告诉我们这个问题是什么语言的
to tell us what language the issue is in
所以这里是提示
So here's the prompt
然后，我们将打印出原始信息的语言和问题
Then we'll print out the original messages language and the issue
然后我们将要求模型将其翻译成英语和韩语
and then we'll ask the model to translate it into English and Korean
所以让我们运行这个。所以，原始信息是法语
So let's run this. So the original message in French
所以我们有各种语言
So we have a variety of languages
然后模型将它们翻译成英语和韩语
and then the model translates them into English and then Korean
你可以看到这里，所以模型说
You can see here, so the model says
这是法语
this is French
所以这是因为这个提示的反应将是，这是法语
So that's because the response from this prompt is going to be, this is French
你可以尝试将这个提示编辑成这样的内容
You could try editing this prompt to say something like
告诉我这是什么语言
tell me what language this is
只用一个词来回答或不用句子
respond with only one word or don't use a sentence
如果你希望这只是一个词的话
that kind of thing if you wanted this to just be one word
或者你可以要求它以JSON格式或类似的东西
or you could ask for it in a JSON format or something like that
这可能会鼓励它不要使用整个句子
which would probably encourage it to not use a whole sentence
因此，令人惊讶的是，你刚刚建立了一个通用翻译器
So amazing, you've just built a universal translator
也可以随时暂停视频，在这里添加任何你想尝试的其他语言
and also feel free to pause the video and add any other languages you want to try here
也许是你自己说的语言
maybe languages you speak yourself
看看这个模型是怎么做的
and see how the model does
因此，我们接下来要深入研究的是语气转换
So the next thing we're going to dive into is tone transformation
写作可以根据目标受众而有所不同
Writing can vary based on an intended audience
我给同事或教授写电子邮件的方式
the way that I would write an e-mail to a colleague or a professor
显然会与我给我弟弟发短信的方式完全不同
is obviously going to be quite different to the way I text my younger brother
所以ChatGPT实际上也可以帮助产生不同的语气
So ChatGPT can actually also help produce different tones
因此，让我们看一些例子
So let's look at some examples
在这第一个例子中
So in this first example
提示是，将以下内容从俚语翻译成商务信函
the prompt is, translate the following from slang to a business letter
老兄，这是乔
Dude, this is Joe
检查一下这盏落地灯的规格
check out the spec on the standing lamp
因此，让我们来执行这个
So let's execute this
正如你所看到的，我们有一封更正式的商业信函
As you can see, we have a much more formal business letter
有一个关于落地灯规格的建议
with a proposal for a standing lamp specification
我们要做的下一件事是在不同的格式之间进行转换
The next thing that we're going to do is to convert between different formats
ChatGPT非常善于在不同的格式之间进行转换，如JSON到HTML
ChatGPT is very good at translating between different formats such as JSON to HTML
XML，各种各样的东西，markdown
XML, all kinds of things, markdown
所以在提示中，我们将描述输入和输出的格式
So in the prompt, we'll describe both the input and the output formats
所以这里有一个例子
So here is an example
所以我们有这样一个JSON
So we have this JSON that
它包含一个餐厅员工的名单，包括他们的名字和电子邮件
contains a list of restaurant employees with their name and e-mail
然后在提示中
Then in the prompt
我们将要求模型将其从JSON翻译成HTML
we're going to ask the model to translate this from JSON to HTML
所以提示是，把下面的Python字典从JSON翻译成
So the prompt is, translate the following Python dictionary from JSON to
HTML，包括列头和标题
HTML with column headers and titles
然后我们将从模型中得到响应并打印出来
Then we'll get the response from the model and print it
所以这里我们有一些HTML显示所有的雇员姓名和电子邮件
So here we have some HTML displaying all of the employee names and e-mails
那么现在让我们来看看我们是否可以作为
So now let's see if we can actually view this HTML
所以我们要使用这个Python库中的这个显示函数
So we're going to use this display function from this Python library
显示 HTML 响应
display HTML response
在这里你可以看到这是一个正确格式化的HTML表格
Here you can see that this is a properly formatted HTML table
我们要做的下一个转换任务是拼写检查和语法检查
The next transformation task we're going to do is spell check and grammar checking
这是ChatGPT的一个非常流行的用途
This is a really popular use for ChatGPT
我强烈建议这样做
I highly recommend doing this
我一直在做这个
I do this all the time
当你用非母语工作时，它尤其有用
It's especially useful when you're working in a non-native language
因此，这里有一些常见的语法和拼写问题的例子
So here are some examples of some common grammar and spelling problems
以及语言模型如何帮助解决这些问题
and how the language model can help address these
所以我将粘贴一个有一些语法或拼写错误的句子列表
So I'm going to paste in a list of sentences that have some grammatical or spelling errors
然后，我们将循环浏览每一个句子
Then we're going to loop through each of these sentences
然后
And
让模型进行校对
ask the model to proofread these.
校对并进行修正。然后我们将使用一些分隔符
Proofread and correct. And then we'll use some delimiters.
然后我们将获取响应并将其打印出来，就像往常一样
And then we will get the response and print it as usual.
就这样，这个模型能够纠正所有这些语法错误
And so the model is able to correct all of these grammatical errors
我们可以使用我们之前讨论过的一些技术
We could use some of the techniques that we've discussed before
因此，为了改进提示，我们可以说校对和纠正以下文字
So to improve the prompt, we could say proofread and correct the following text
并重写
And rewrite
哦
Oh
并重写整个
And rewrite the whole
并重写
And rewrite it
改正后的版本
Corrected version
如果你没有发现任何错误，就说没有发现错误
If you don't find any errors, just say no errors found
让我们来试试这个
Let's try this
因此，这种方式我们能够，哦，他们在这里仍然使用引号
So this way we were able to, oh, they're still using quotes here
但你可以想象，你能够找到一种方法，用一点点的
But you can imagine you'd be able to find a way with a little bit of
迭代提示开发
iterative prompt development to
找到一种更可靠的提示方式，每一次都能正常工作
kind of find a prompt that works more reliably every single time
因此，现在我们将实现另一个例子
And so now we'll do another example
在你把你的文本发布到公共论坛之前，检查它总是有用的
It's always useful to check your text before you post it in a public forum
因此，我们将通过一个检查评论的例子
And so we'll go through an example of checking a review
这里有一个关于毛绒熊猫的评论
And so here is a review about a stuffed panda
因此，我们将要求模型校对和纠正评论
And so we're going to ask the model to proofread and correct the review
很好。所以我们有了这个更正的版本
Great. So we have this corrected version
我们可以做的一件很酷的事情是找到
And one cool thing we can do is find
我们的原始评论和模型的输出之间的差异
the kind of differences between our original review and the model's output
所以我们要基于这个Redlines Python包来做这个
So we're going to use this red lines Python package to do this
我们将得到以下的差异
And we're going to get the diff between
我们评论的原文和模型的输出之间的差异
the original text of our review and the model output
然后显示这个
and then display this
所以在这里你可以看到原始评论和模型输出之间的差异
And so here you can see the diff between the original review
和模型输出之间的差异，以及那些已经被纠正的东西
and the model output and the kind of things that have been corrected
因此，我们使用的提示是校对和纠正这个评论
So the prompt that we use was proofread and correct this review
但你也可以做一些更戏剧性的改变
But you can also make kind of more dramatic changes
语气的变化，以及诸如此类的事情
kind of changes to tone and that kind of thing
因此，让我们再试一试
So let's try one more thing
所以在这个提示中，我们将要求模特校对和纠正
So in this prompt, we're going to ask the model to proofread and correct
同样的评论，但也要使其更有说服力，并确保其
the same review, but also make it more compelling and ensure that it
遵循APA风格，并针对高级读者
follows APA style and targets an advanced reader
我们还将要求以Markdown格式输出结果
And we're also going to ask for the output in markdown format
因此，我们在这里使用原始审查的相同文本
And so we're using the same text from the original review up here
因此，让我们来执行这个
So let's execute this
在这里，我们有一个扩展的APA风格的毛绒熊猫的评论
And here we have a expanded APA style review of the soft Panda
因此，这是它的转换视频
So this is it for the transforming video
接下来，我们将使用扩写功能，采取较短的提示
Next up, we have expanding where we'll take a shorter prompt
并从语言模型中产生一个更长、更自由的反应
and kind of generate a longer, more freeform response from a language model